Meghan Martin

Product designer and creative developer

@ meghanxmartin@gmail.com

% www.meghan.work

EDUCATION

M.A. Design Strategy

Instituto Europeo di Design

 Coursework: UX/UI Design, User Research, Visual Design, Design Thinking, Branding Strategy, Communication Strategy, Research Methods and Processes, Product Strategy, Social Impact and Sustainable Design

B.A. Political Economy

University of California at Berkeley

 Leadership: Design Director at Fashion and Student Trends, Creative Lead at BARE Magazine, International Project Coordinator at World Literacy Project, Giant Slalom competitor

EXPERIENCE

Product Designer (Contract)

Covid Science Engine

m 05/2020 - Ongoing

- Designed an application for COVID-19 researchers that brings the time of digesting research from minutes to less than 30 seconds
- Created style guide and UI library that was implemented in React
- Led front-end development team to implementation
- Collaborated with larger team of two virologists, three front end developers, one backend developer and two machine learning data scientists

Product Designer and Developer (Contract)

Los Arabis Vineyards

1 04/2020 - 07/2020

- Redesigned an outdated ecommerce website and implemented design with custom Shopify development
- Led project through the phases of discovery, style guides, branding process, prototypes, development and user testing
- Increased metrics of restaurant contracts, sales channels and online sales

Product Designer and Developer

Freelance

02/2020 - Ongoing

- Creating UI/UX strategies including wireframes, mockups, visual identities and end-to-end user flows
- Clients include hospitality company, education nonprofit, advocacy organization and COVID-19 machine learning application

Product Designer and Strategic Consultant

IED Madrid

1 01/2019 - 12/2019

 UX/UI design and strategy for clients including ArcelorMittal, NH Hotel Group, 40+ location restaurant chain, international development organization, an email marketing SaaS product and an esports startup

SKILLS

Accessibility Product Strategy Visual Design

Product Strategy Visual Design

Prototyping

SUMMARY

Driven and solution oriented product designer who loves to code and is passionate about crafting meaningful user experiences.

Experienced in web and mobile application design, front end programming and product strategy. I believe that doing is better than not doing, to always show up imperfectly, keep it simple and keep your ego out of it.

You can see more of my skillset and relevant design work at www.meghan.work.

CERTIFICATIONS

Interaction Design Specialization

University of California, San Diego

Full Stack Web Development:
Javascript, Ruby on Rails, HTML/CSS

Le Wagon

Visual Design and Branding, React.js, Animation for the Web, AJAX & APIs SuperHi

PROJECTS

Fonts in the Wild

Designed and shipped <u>Fonts in the Wild</u>, a design resource to find free and paid font inspiration for commercial and personal projects

Fancier

During Le Wagon bootcamp, I led UX/UI design and on a team developed a social marketplace for preloved festival outfits; you can watch me pitch a demo of mobile-first Fancier live here

ACHIEVEMENTS



Featured Product Hunt Maker

<u>Launched product</u> currently at 2nd Product Hunt featured position for launch day at 450+ upvotes and 5/5 average reviews; Fonts in the Wild is used by thousands of users weekly



Team MVP

During Q1 of 2019, nominated MVP at Oracle due to new hire mentorship and highest quota attainment of an average of 228%